DREW JEX

Full Stack Software Architect

drewjex28@gmail.com 385-375-0254 linkedin.com/in/drewjex portfolio.drewjex.com

About Me

Enthusiastic software architect specializing in JavaScript web application development and rich UI design. Check out my portfolio at portfolio.drewjex.com.

Top Skills

JavaScript (ES6+) web application development

- → React, Babel, Webpack
- → NodeJS, NPM, Express

UI Design/Development

- → Mobile and Web Design
- → SASS, HTML, CSS
- → Responsive Design

.NET development

- → C#, WPF
- → MVVM framework
- → Visual Studio

PHP back end development

→ MySQL, SQL Server, MVC

Experience

Software Engineer · SkyWest Airlines · May 2017 - Present

Built and revamped critical JavaScript web applications, improving performance and load-time by 30%.

Trained and led employees on best practices in MVVM architecture and building reusable front end components.

Lead Full-Stack Web Developer • BYU Campus Life • July 2014 - April 2017

Led the design, developoment, and deployment of 10+ high-priority web apps spanning several departments.

Improved performance and design for high-traffic event-ticketing site exceeding 40,000 users.

Interacted directly with clients to design and develop high-quality UI interfaces for both web/mobile devices.

Software and Desktop Support Volunteer • LDS Church • July 2013 - December 2013

Designed and developed flexible, multilingual web applications used by church members in 5+ countries.

Oversaw deployment of supply-management application, streamlining delivery operations and minimizing errors.

Web Developer · BYU Health & Human Performance Services · July 2011 - May 2012

Responsible for spearheading development of complex online reporting system in HTML and Javascript.

Education

B.S. from Brigham Young University: Computer Science (April 2017)

Dean's List BYU College of Physical and Mathematical Sciences

Awarded ORCA Research Grant for development of cutting-edge music-generating software

OpenSource Projects · github.com/drewjex

Grid · github.com/drewjex/Grid-Playground

→ Project testing capability of HTML5 Canvas element served by NodeJS Express server using web-sockets.

MusicMaker · github.com/drewjex/MusicMaker-v2

→ Spontaneously generates music in 3 seconds or less by analyzing patterns in other music.

Custom WPF components · github.com/drewjex/WPFComponents

→ Custom front end and back-end components built for WPF and .NET development.